<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HalideOS</title>
    <link>https://dsc-kiit.github.io/project-halide/docs/Getting-Started/</link>
    <description>Recent content on HalideOS</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dsc-kiit.github.io/project-halide/docs/Getting-Started/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://dsc-kiit.github.io/project-halide/docs/Getting-Started/Introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsc-kiit.github.io/project-halide/docs/Getting-Started/Introduction/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to Operating Systems Development #  Please proceed with a really good grasp of C/C++ If you landed here then, congratulations! You are about to take on one of the most challenging projects in Software Engineering, that is, developing an Operating System. There are no proper roadmaps, no copy-paste code and lots of theory. You&amp;rsquo;ll be guided solely by passion and you will truly peak once you dive into the depths of OS Dev.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://dsc-kiit.github.io/project-halide/docs/Getting-Started/Required-Knowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsc-kiit.github.io/project-halide/docs/Getting-Started/Required-Knowledge/</guid>
      <description>Required Knowledge #    Basic Computer Science - You should have a good grasp on theorertical concepts like binary and hexadecimal systems, data structures and algorithms and abstraction among other things.
  Programming - You need to be familar with the nooks and crannies of languages like C and C++. On top of that, good coding practices are something you have to follow for it is not okay to write inefficient software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://dsc-kiit.github.io/project-halide/docs/Getting-Started/Resources-and-Tutorials/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsc-kiit.github.io/project-halide/docs/Getting-Started/Resources-and-Tutorials/</guid>
      <description>Resources and Tutorials #  A massive list of all sorts of tutorials, books and videos on operating systems.
Web #    Wiki OS Dev - Provides information and a community  Wiki Low level Community - A TODO list of what needs to be done  OS Tutorial - Several step-by-step README tutorials and code samples  Books #    Writing a Simple Operating System - A 77 page masterpiece by Nick Blundell  The Little Book about OS Development - A practical guide to writing your own x86 operating system by Eric Helen and Adam Roseberg  Operating System Concepts - An introduction to essential concepts by Galvin and Silberschatz  Modern Operating Systems - By Andrew Tanenbaum and Herbert Bos  Operating Systems: Three Easy Pieces - All about virtualization, concurrency and persistance by Andrea C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://dsc-kiit.github.io/project-halide/docs/Getting-Started/Running-and-Compiling-Halide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsc-kiit.github.io/project-halide/docs/Getting-Started/Running-and-Compiling-Halide/</guid>
      <description>Running and Compiling HalideOS on your System #  Running HalideOS in Oracle Virtual Box #   Head over to the Releases section of the GitHub repository and download the halide.iso file.   Open up Oracle VM VirtualBox. Click on New.   Put HalideOS as the name. Set Type to Other and Version to Other/Unknown.   Set the memory size. 64 MB will be enough.   Click on Next and select Do not add a virtual disk and click on Create.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>